Lombard General Insurance Company
Limited Q4 and FI 2025 earnings
conference call from the senior
management we have with us today Mr.
Sanjiv Mantri MD and CEO of the company
Mr. Gopal Balchandran CFO Mr. Girish
Nyak chief technology and health
underwriting and claims Mr. Sep Kuradyia
chief corporate solutions international
bank assurance Mr. Anand Singhi chief
retail and government business Mr. the
core of Aurora chief reinsurance
underwriting and claims for property and
casualty. Please note that any
statements comments are made in today's
call that may look like forward-looking
statements are based on information
presently available to the management
and do not constitute any indication of
any future performance as future
involves risk and uncertainties which
could cause results to differ materially
from the current views being expressed.
As a reminder, all participant lines
will be in the listenon only mode and
there will be an opportunity for you to
ask questions after the presentation
concludes. Should you need assistance
during the conference call, please
signal an operator by pressing star then
zero on your touch on phone. I now hand
the conference over to Mr. Sanjiv
Mantri, MD and CEO ICIC Lumbard General
Insurance Limited. Thank you and over to
you.
Good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earning conference
call at ICL Lumbar General Insurance
Company Limited for quarter 4 and
financial year
2025. Let me give you a brief overview
of the trends we observed in the economy
as well as the industry followed by an
overview of the
business. Post this our CFO Mr. Gopal
Walachendran will share the financial
performance of the company for the
quarter and the year ended 31st March
2025. The the GDP growth for the quarter
ended December 2024 stood at 6.2% versus
5.6% for the quarter ended September
2024. As per the data released by Moxy,
high frequency indicators like eway
bills, stoll collections, diesel
consumption and GST collections during
quarter 4 of financial year 2025 are all
indicating positive economic conditions.
Further, Mopsy has revised the fullear
GDP estimates to 6.5% on Feb 28, 2025
versus 6.4% published on Jan 7,
2025. Let me not dwell on certain
industry trends which can have an impact
on the general insurance industry at
large. As indicated during the last
quarter, the government expenditure
remained flat which impacted the
commercial line segment growth for the
current quarter. However, we have
started seeing an uptick in government
spending towards capital expenditure in
past few months. This may be a positive
for the commercial line of business. For
the auto industry, we had seen a growth
in rural market in Q3 of 2025.
Specifically for two-wheer segment at
12.7% and the tractor segment at 20.1%.
as reported by far. However, in quarter
4 2025, we have seen a degrowth of 1.9%
for the two-heer segment and a degrowth
of 4.6% for the tractor segment. This
indicates a softer rural demand. The
private car segment grew by 1.1% and the
commercial vement vehicle segment had a
degrowth of 3.8% 8% for quarter 4
financial year
2025 as reported by far which had an
impact on motor insurance growth for
quarter 4 financial year 2025. However,
for the coming year, the auto industry
is expected to have mid singledigit
growth. We remain positive for the motor
insurance business with increasing
penetration in the old vehicle segments.
The health segment continues to be one
of the fastest growing segments and is
the largest contributor to the industry
constituting 38.1% of the GDP mix for
financial year 2025. However, the
industry growth in financial year 2025
was impacted due to the one by
accounting norm and lower growth in the
health segment health benefit segment
attributable to lower disbburment by of
credit by NBFC's and MFIs. We believe
that the increasing demand for health
protection coupled with increased
medical inflation may drive doubledigit
growth in the health segment in the
coming
year. There were some key economic
changes which were announced during
quarter 4 financial year
2025. The budgetary announcement of
income tax relief provided is expected
to result in an additional 1 trillion in
the hands of Indian taxpaying population
thereby leading to a high disposable
income. The second consecutive interest
rate cut tweaking of norms applicable to
NBSC lending coupled with inclusion of
liquidity by RBI should also support
credit
growth. These policy changes aim to
encourage spending and investment. They
are also expected to stimulate demand
for goods and services thereby boosting
consumption and preparing demand for
risk protection through insurance
solutions.
However, we remain vigilant on the
ongoing geopolitical developments which
may pose risk to both global growth and
the Indian
economy. Now, let me give you a brief
give you an update on the regulatory
developments. The regulatory the
authority during financial year 2025
continued with various reforms seeking
to expand the market and increase the
penetration of insurance product towards
the mission of insurance for all by
2047.
I would like to mention key circulars
which were introduced in quarter 4 2025
regarding capping the increase in senior
citizens health insurance premium rates
to 10% peranom and introduction of
beimma asba facility for health
insurance policies. We believe these
regulatory changes will improve
affordability and create operational
ease for policy
holders. Overall, we remain positive
that the GI industry is poised to grow
in the medium to long term given the
favorable economic and regulatory
environment, low penetration and
relatively higher disposable
income. Now coming to the industry
performance for quarter 4 and financial
year
2025. The gross direct premium income
grew by 1.7% and 6.2% for quarter 4 2025
and financial year 2025 respectively.
Excluding the impact of the one by
accounting norm, the GDPI grew by 8.6%
for financial year
2025. Excluding crop and math health,
the GDPI grew by 4.9% and 8% for quarter
4 2025 and financial year 2025
respectively. Speaking on the specific
segments within the industry, the
commercial segment reported a marginal
degrowth of 1.2% 2% and growth of 1.5%
for quarter 4 and financial year 2025.
Within this, the fire segment registered
a
deg. 5.3% for quarter 4 financial year
2025 and financial year 2025
respectively on account of pricing
pressures excluding the fire segment.
The over overall commercial segment grew
by 8 and a half% for financial year
2025.
The motor segment grew by 6.9% for
quarter 4 of financial year 2025 and 8%
for financial year 2025. The growth in
the segment has been lower due to muted
vehicle sales and continued pricing
pressures reflected by high industry
combined
ratio. The health the health segment
grew at 3.7% and 9% for quarter 4 2025
and financial year 2025. Within this
group health grew at 4.5% and 10.6% for
quarter 4 2025 and financial year 2025
respectively and retail health grew at
7.6% and 12.1% in quarter 4 2025 and
financial year 2025 respectively.
Looking at the underlying performance of
the industry, you may recall our
discussion a year back during our
earnings call where we expect we where
we expected some semblance in
underwriting discipline in the market
due to improvement in the industry's
combined ratio during that period.
However, the combined ratio for the
industry has actually worsened to
113.2% for 9 month as against 112.2% 2%
for 9 months financial year 2024. The
combined ratio for the private sector
has worsened to triple 1.21% for 9
months 2025 from 108.3% for 9 month
financial year 2024. The industry
worsening was largely due to motor
segment combined ratio which increased
to
123.8% in 9 month financial year 2025 as
against
118.2% in 9 month financial year 2024.
Our continued focus on driving
profitable growth helped us to improve
our combined ratio from
103.7% in 9 month financial year 2024 to
102.8% in 9 month financial year 2025
and
103.3% in full financial year 2024 to
102.6% in financial for the financial
year 2025 on NBC
basis. I will now walk you through the
company performance across key business
segments during quarter 4 and financial
year
2025. The company's GDPR registered a
growth of 8% for quarter 4 2025 and 11%
for financial year 2025 on N basis with
the 1 byN accounting norm for quarter 4
2025 the company registered a growth of
2.3% is as against the industry growth
of 1.7%.
And for financial year 2025, the company
registered a growth of 8.3% as again the
industry growth of
6.2%. Excluding crop and mass health,
the company's growth was 2.2% and
7.7%. Compared to the industry growth of
4.9% and 8% for quarter 4 2025 and
financial year 2025
respectively. In the commercial line
segment in quarter 4 2025 our growth was
at 2.8% as against the industry deg
growth of 1.2%. For financial year 2025
we grew by 2.5
2.1% as against the industry growth of 1
and a half% thereby maintaining market
share. This indicates the strength of a
brand relationship and service quality
in an environment where industry faced
continued pricing pressure throughout
the year. In the fire segment, we grew
in line with the industry. And in marine
cargo, engineering and liability lines
of business, we reported growth higher
than the industry leading to market
share
accretion. In motor segment, we grew
at.1% for quarter 4 2025 as again the
industry growth of
6.9%. We continue to drive our motor
strategy based on granular portfolio
segmentation and prudent risk selection.
For the financial year 2025, we grew by
11 and a half% as again the industry
growth of 8%. Consequently, our market
shares grew to 10.8% for financial year
2025 versus 10.5% for financial year
2024. The portfolio mix for private car,
two-wheer and CV stood at
53.4%,
25.4% and 21.2% respectively. Our
continued focus on multi- channelannel
distribution, underwriting capabilities
and efficient claim settlement and
actual practices helped us in
maintaining a leadership
position. Moving to the health segment,
we grew by
22.1% and 19.2% for quarter 4 financial
year 2025 and financial year 2025
respectively. With the one byan
accounting norm by 9.7% and 12.6% 6% for
quarter 4 2025 and financial year 2025
respectively. Our retail health segment
registered a growth at 47.7% for quarter
4 financial year 2025 with the 1 byN
accounting norm. The growth of quarter 4
2025 was 25.1% as against the industry
growth of 7.6%.
For financial year 2025, the overall
growth stood at
38.1%. With one by an accounting norm,
the growth for financial year 2025 was
25%. As again the industry growth of
12.1%. As a result, we gained market
share from 3% in financial year 2024 to
3.3% for financial year 2025.
The group health employed employee
segment witnessed growth of 24.9% and
18.5% for quarter 4 2025 and financial
year
2025 respectively. A group other
business debut by 5.5% and will be won
by an accounting norm that the growth
was 30% for quarter 4
2025. For financial year 2025, group
other business had a muted growth of
5.3% on account of impact on health
benefit business through the banker
channel with the one by accounting norm.
This segment showed a degrowth of 10.5%
for the
year. We had spoken about various one
team initiatives in earlier earnings
call. One of the initiatives we had
spoken about for the consolidation of
customerf facing digital effects like
take care helps app website and digital
alliances under one digital to deliver a
superior customer experience and to
drive efficiency. Some of the digital
outcomes achieved in financial year 2025
include increasing unique customer visit
by 2x on our digital platform. 37%
growth in fresh transactions on our
digital platform. Downloads for our
one-stop solution one take your app
surpass surpassed 14.9
million. The business done through the
app stood at 9 927.7 million and 2653.2
2 million for quarter 4, financial year
2025 and financial year 2025
respectively. Consequently, our
customerf facing digital asset business
grew by
15.8% constituting 6.6% of our overall
GDP for financial year 2025.
Now I would like to share with you some
initiatives taken by us for improving
the customer experience and driving
efficiencies for
claims. On the motor side, a preferred
partner network service
74.1% of our nonm claims in quarter 4
2025 up from 69.6% in quarter 4 2024.
For financial year 2025, this number
stood at 73.2%. 2% up from 65% in
financial year
2024. Our cloud calling facilities were
used by 89.6% of our motor customers in
quarter 4 financial year 2025 as against
77% in quarter 4 2024. For the full year
this number was at 86% as against 49%
previous year. This resulted in a
reduction of cost to claim ratio by 21%
for the
year.
Our average claim settlement period for
retail lines of business has seen
improvement from 6 days in financial
year 2024 to 5 days in financial year
2025 for motor and for motor and for
five and for 5 days in financial year
2024 to 3 days in financial year 2025
for health. Our is act initiative which
was launched in April 2024 offered an
onground claim support to over 90,000
customers across 56 cities and 25
hospital network in financial year
2025. A focus on customer experience and
process efficiencies has led to healthy
NPS of 67 and 69 for health and motor
claims respectively for 9 months
2025. With all the above efforts, we are
pleased to share that the company's
premium growth has been higher by 210
basis points as against the industry
growth. Our focus on driving profitable
opportunities
has combined ratio from
103.3% in financial year 2024 to 102.6%
in financial year 2025 on n basis on on
the 1 by n accounting norm the combined
ratio stood at 102.8% 8% leading to a
pad growth of
30.7% and then delivering ROE for the
year at 19.1%.
As we enter into the new financial year,
we remain committed to achieving the
desired scale through creation of
positive customer experiences,
leveraging data analytics and a
technology first approach harnessing a
multi-roduct multi-distribution strategy
and with a continued focus on product
innovation. With a core philosophy of
one team, we continue to scale up the
profit pool and to drive sustainable
growth.
I will now request Gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for the
recently concluded quarter and financial
year. Thanks Sanjie and uh good evening
to each one of you. I will now give you
a brief overview of the financial
performance for the recently concluded
quarter and the financial year. We have
uploaded the results presentation on our
website. You can access it as we walk
you through the performance numbers with
effect from October 1, 2024. Long-term
products are accounted on a 1 byN basis
as mandated by the regulator and Q4 and
FI25 numbers are not comparable with
prior periods. For more details on the
impact, refer to slide number 15 of our
investor presentation for further
details. The gross direct minimum income
of the company was at rupes 268.33
billion in FI25 as against rupes 247.76
billion in FI24. A growth of 8.3% as
against industry growth of 6.2%. 2%. GDP
of the company was at 62.11 billion in
Q4 FI25 as against 60.73 billion in Q4
FI24. A growth of 2.3% as against
industry growth of
1.7%. On the retail side of the
business, GDP of the motor segment was
at 107.4 billion in FI25 as against
96.34 billion in FI24, registering a
growth of 11.5%.
The advanced premium for the motor
segment was at rupes 37.17 billion at
March 31, 2025 as against 36.44 billion
as at December 31, 2024. GDP of the
health segment was at rupes 69.5 billion
in FI25 as against 61.71 billion in FI24
registering a growth of 12.6%. Our agent
which includes the point of sale
distribution count was at 1 lakh 40,736
as at March 31 2025 up from 1 lakh 40,77
as at December 31 2024. GDP of our
commercial line segment was at 69.95
billion in FI25 as against 68.51 billion
in FI24 registering a growth of 2.1% as
against industry growth of
1.5%. Resultedly our combined ratio
stood at 102.8% 8% for FI25 as against
103.3% for FI24 excluding the impact of
CAT losses of 94 billion in FI25 and
1.37 billion in FI24. The combined ratio
was 102.4% and 102.5% respectively.
Combined ratio for quarter 4 FI25 was
102.5% as against 102.3% in quarter 4
FI24. Our investment assets during the
quarter rose to rupes 535.0 08 billion
as at March 31 2025 up from rupees
515.99 97 billion as of December 31 2024
our investment leverage net of
borrowings was 3.74 times as at March 31
2025 as against 3.76 times at December
31 2024 investment income was at 42.5
billion in FI25 as against 36.1 billion
in FI24 on a quarterly basis investment
income was at 8.77 billion in Q4 Q4 FI25
as against 9.54 billion in Q4
FI24. Our capital net of impairment on
investment assets stood at rupees 8.02
billion for the full year as compared to
5.51 billion in the previous financial
year. Capital gains net of impairment on
investment assets stood at
rupees.06 billion in quarter 4 FI25 as
compared to rupees 1.56 billion in
quarter 4 FI24. Our profit before tax
grew by 30% at 33.21 billion in FI25 as
against 25.55 billion in FI24. Whereas
PBT grew by 4.2% at 6.68 billion in
quarter 4 FI25 as against 6.98 billion
rupees in quarter 4 FI24. Consequently,
profit after tax grew by 30.7% at 25.08
08 billion in FI25 as against 19.19
billion in FI24. PAT regroup by 1.9% to
rupees 5.1 billion in Q4 FI25 as against
5.19 billion in quarter 4 FI24. The
board of directors of the company has
proposed a final dividend of rupees 7
per share for FI25. This statement is
however subject to approval of
shareholders in the ensuing annual
general meeting of the company. The
overall dividend for FI25 including the
proposed final dividend is rupes 12.5
per share. Last year the overall
dividend was rupees 11 per share. Return
on average equity was 19.1% in FI25 as
against 17.2% in FI24. Return on equity
for quarter 4 this year was 14.5 as
against 17.8 in quarter 4 of last year.
Solveny ratio was at 2.69 69 times at
March 31, 2025 as against 2.36 times at
December 31, 2024 continued to be higher
than the regulatory minimum requirement
of 1.5. As I conclude, I would like to
assert that we remain focused on our
strategy of driving profitable growth,
consistent and sustainable value
creation for all our stakeholders while
ensuring that the interest of policy
holders is in the forefront at all
times. I'd like to thank you all for
attending this earnings call and we will
be happy to take any questions that you
may have. Thank you.
Thank you. We will now begin the
question and answer session. Anyone who
wishes to ask a question may press star
and one on the touchstone telephone. If
you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue, you may press star and
two. Participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question. Ladies
and gentlemen, we'll wait for a moment
while the question Q as
samples. The first question comes on the
line of P chain from MLA OS financial
services limited. Please go ahead. Yeah.
Hi. Uh a good set of numbers on
especially on the combined ratio fund.
Uh just your thoughts on uh you know how
do we see the growth from here? uh
personally know from a overall BWP
perspective uh given the one by impact
would continue uh to be there in one
match of next one of FI26 and second
half would see unwinding of uh the GWP
uh and contributing to some part of
growth. So that would be uh the first
question. Uh second question would be on
your combined ratio whether you would
look at combined ratio further improving
from the one that reported uh in in the
for
FI25 and uh bit on the fire segment if
you could highlight you know what are
the kind of renewals we've seen in
January and uh also in in the uh in the
April renewals and those will be my
three questions. Thanks.
Okay. Yeah. Thanks P. I think uh with
respect to the growth uh even when I was
reading in terms of uh what it is line
by line ad but again I I'll talk about
it uh motor per say expecting the new
sale
missross by other OEM as to what they
are seeing. I believe the base on the
private car in particular is high. Uh I
also spoke about the fact that the
quarter four two wheeler numbers were
were negative which was a bit of a
surprise as what we saw in quarter three
and commercial vehicle I would be more
positive overall because government
capex and lot of other activities which
in the last
financial should get picked up. So net
net motor we will see single digit to
maybe just about double digit growth is
what our prediction is and look all of
these things can change real time we'll
keep you updated but that's what our
belief is on the health side p our own
belief is we will should see double
digit growth uh now health is two
components retail health and as well as
the group health part of it I'm more
clearly talking about the retail health
path which will continue to see far more
uh incremental business in terms of new
to insurance and also there would be
whatever interest rate growth that comes
out in terms of overall risk. So we
would remain positive on health and
health with a 38% contribution will not
be surprised if we see that contribution
probably going to a 40% thereabout and
becomes the largest and will continue to
be the largest player. The last but uh
not the least in terms of the commercial
line of business. Uh we've had a very
one of the most difficult years on
commercial line. If you see uh we've
never seen a growth of this nature going
to you know no single digit in last 7 to
years clearly it had multiple factors
fire pricing which we spoke about it
however going forward as the and you
spoke about and I'll probably talk about
the other question that you put across
we saw a lot of semblance in the
industry overall on the fire
side and on that basis we do believe and
we do see relatively much better numbers
on fire and with the activity on the
capex which is coming through
engineering line of business should also
do well. So overall commercial we would
like to believe that there should be a
there should be back to a double digit
kind of a growth at the industry level.
I think your last question was on the
combine on the combine. All right. So I
think P again if you look at what we
have been saying is uh obviously our
performance will will be in the context
of how the market uh performs. Uh so
which is why we kind of also put that
out as a part of the opening uh
transcript as in to say that at the
beginning of the financial year
concluded we had kind of possibly
expected a lot more semblance to pay out
but in reality if you look at I think
the market seems to have gone slightly
more in that sense north I think
combined ratios have kind of increased
by almost 100 basis point at an
aggregate level so obviously we'll wait
for the full year numbers to play out in
terms of what the players report but
obviously we will be at it when it comes
comes to let's say driving profitable
opportunities. So hence the endeavor
will be obviously to try and see how we
can create lot more efficiencies whether
it is on loss ratios cost etc etc and
obviously ris select the right portfolio
mix but obviously we will see how the
market direction plays out and in that
context is how we would also want to see
our combined play through but having
said that definitely I think the gap
between us and the industry combined
whichever way you look at it I think
obviously we will be able to kind of do
lot more uh positives to play out and in
the aggregate I think what we have
spoken about is time and again we will
look for trying to see if we can do that
improvement in the return on equity that
we can give to stakeholders uh the range
that we have generally spoken about in
that range of 16 to 18% the endeavor
will be to obviously try and see over
the long term to move towards the 18 to
20 depending on how the market plays out
yeah so I think and so the simple answer
is uh would we like to improve our
combine uh certainly yes uh and as Gopal
mentioned uh we saw a trajectory when we
came in last year where industry combine
had shown an improvement on the basis
that we felt we will go uh we also would
like to see a similar thing but the
duration happened and the duration most
happened in terms of motor moving from
118 to 123 for a 9 month combined but so
that being said we will let uh these
things play out uh and in our mind the
single factor that drives is are we
generate the roy and That's what largely
Gopal is speaking about is uh as far as
we as a you know uh as an entity is
concerned.
That's just your thoughts on motor to be
prioritized. That will be my last.
So we always remain hopeful but uh no
news as yet. So uh is the industry
seeking it? Answer is yes. Is it come
through? The answer is
no in that sense. Yeah. Yeah. Okay.
Yeah, thank you so much.
Thanks.
Thank you. A reminder to all the
participants in the interest of time
please restrict questions to two per
participants. Next question comes from
the line of Sankit Koda with Aendaspar.
Please go ahead.
Yeah, thank you for the opportunity
Gopal. In the current quarter we seems
to have done little more reinsurance
accepted business because there is a
meaningful difference between G GDPI and
GWP in the quarter almost 10 percentage.
So s just wanted to understand the color
of this business and um do you see uh
opportunity and reinsurance accepted
with price hikes going up probably you
will do the same kind of a business in
in subsequent year also. uh any any
thoughts on those lines just just want
to understand and and the second
question uh was that uh uh see see if
you if you could not book capital gains
in the current quarter uh your your
yield remained at 6.3 suppose
hypothetically market remains weak
largely for fi26 so so is it fair to say
that your 6.3 6.4 four is the yield for
for uh for for probably for the entire
FI26 and therefore we need to look ro
from from that perspective. Uh just
wanted to understand that a bit from you
and lastly data keeping question if you
can give retail health loss ratio
breakup and motor GWP break up into new
and old which you usually do. Thank you.
Yeah, maybe I think I'll first uh do the
data keeping question first uh which is
something that keeps coming to us every
quarter. Uh so I'm just kind of giving
you the numbers both for Q4 of last year
and Q4 of this year first and then I
will give the numbers for the full year
in terms of the break up between
corporate health and uh the retail
indity numbers. Uh so quarter 4 of last
year corporate health uh loss ratios
were
88.1%. And the retail indemnity numbers
again for quarter 4 of last year was
64.6%.
Visually this quarter four of this year
corporate health is at
97.2%. And retail health broadly the
range that we have spoken about is at
about
64.8%. On a full year basis this number
for corporate health stands at about
93.7 last year and the current year I
mean again last year retail indemnity
numbers is
65.4 year this number for corporate
health is at 97.6 six and retail
indemnity is
67.9. So that's the numbers in terms of
the break up between corporate health
and retail health. Now coming to your
point first question on reinsurance
accepted uh one at an aggregate level
obviously if you ask us underwriting
philosophy is to drive profitable growth
whether it is with respect to the gross
direct premium income that we write or
even with respect to let's say the
reinsurances acceptances to the extent
whatever we do. So therefore from a
philosophy standpoint one thing we will
stand committed to driving profitable
growth across the revenue streams that
we source. Having said that I think if
you look at at an aggregate level I
think in terms of the roughly the
premium that we would have written of
close to about 28,000 crores or
thereabout the extent of reinsurance in
world will be a single-digit number. Um
so hence to that extent I think a large
part of the opportunities is what we see
clearly even in the domestic market.
Plus at the same time obviously we look
for given the fact that we also have an
office in our IO uh business we would
want to kind of continue to see how we
can leverage profitable opportunities
even through the IIO business. So hence
that is how we would kind of play
through whether a particular business
comes through in a quarter or otherwise
I think again as I keep saying our
business is significantly cyclical and
wherever we see opportunities play out
is how you will continue to see the mix
of business between direct ra etc etc
play out the larger number to look at
will be more on an annual basis that
will be more reflective of where we are
in terms of our approach to writing
domestic and reinsurance in world second
point on Uh yeah sorry for so so I was
asking this question predominantly
because because you you will see a
better pricing environment uh in next
fiscal year. So so if other segments
slow down say motor slows down a bit
because of the weak auto cycle. uh is it
fair to say that this product might be
an opportunity stick uh approach to to
uh to to drive the overall growth maybe
from that perspective because I think
environment
exactly so your point is absolutely
right that's exactly what I said I think
if you ask us for us both of them are
preferred areas of opportunity so
therefore to that extent where we see uh
preferable segments for us to be able to
underwrite we will look at both will it
suddenly become a very large proportion
of our overall revenue streams at this
point of time clearly not but obviously
we will look at uh the as I said
profitable opportunities between
domestic and the reinsurance inward and
the revenues that we'll eventually
source will be mix of both
uh on your point on capital gains I
think uh if you look at the uh approach
that we have taken in so far as uh
building the investment portfolio is
concerned I think uh the treasury team
has done a brilliant job uh in terms of
how to kind of balance the mix of asset
classes between equity and the fixed
income portfolio and that's the reason
during this last periods of high
interest rate regime we have been able
to kind of significantly go long and
which is the reason I think even in our
earlier earlier earnings call we have
spoken about of our duration of the book
that still continues to be slightly in
excess of uh 5.3 years and if you look
at the yield to maturity uh the yield to
maturity of the book also currently
stands at about 7.55%.
And hence uh and this is what is kind of
translating into if you look at our
marktomarket positions on the overall
investment book while on the roughly an
aggregate mark to market gain as on the
balance sheet date of roughly about 1800
uh 18 billion um in terms of the mark to
market unrealized gains is what we have.
So I think the portfolio is well
positioned. The question to ask for is
what happens in case if you see possibly
sustained periods of price competition
or sustained periods of low interest
rate regime. Now all of that I think in
so in in so far as the second part of
let's say periods of low interest rate
sustaining in the next year I think to
that extent I think our duration call
will kind of largely reflect that and of
course incre reinvestment of the
incremental cash flows will get
subjected to getting placed at a lower
interest rate and that will be true for
the entire market. So therefore the
entire market will have to work much
more harder in terms of improving the
pricing and therefore on balance which
is what we keep saying I think the roe
range that we will work which will be
through a combination of driving
underwriting outcomes and return on
investment that will be in the range of
18 to 20%. assuming the market obviously
shows signs of change and also you know
sake now I'll just give you the you know
lay of the land uh if you go back in
time in April uh as we were finishing
our financial year
2024 if you would have told us to guess
the growth rate for commercial line of
business we would have said definitely
it will be in double digits uh if you
would have told us on the banker line of
business which is a big practice we have
again we would have said a decent and
with double digits but as transpired in
the course of the year both of these
lines that are relatively difficult here
but again the emphasis that we have as a
multi-line multi-ro companies are we
agile enough to toggle uh even you look
at the numbers that you see quarter and
quarter in motor we had a significant
gain in quarter 1 and quarter two and
again in quarter three and quarter
four we have the PSUs which have built
up severe intensity which is not making
much of an economic sense
and you have seen us growing relatively
low while we finished the year overall
with a gain on market share. So what I'm
trying to emphasize to all of you is uh
what we see and what comes through there
can be a gap and as an organization we
are expected to maintain that level of
agility to make those shifts happen and
what we predict not necessarily the way
the market will end up behaving. So you
we will have to factor that and again I
come back in light of that the focus
intently for us as an organization boils
down to are we able to generate the you
know uh that is expected by all our
stakeholders.
All right good. Yeah
please rejoin the queue for
mr. Please rejoin the queue for more
questions.
Thank you.
Next question comes from the line of
Nidesh Jen with Invest. Please go
ahead. Uh thanks, thanks for the
opportunity. So two question. First is
on fire pricing. Are we already seeing
signs of improvement in fire pricing for
the industry?
Yeah, the answer is yes, there is uh uh
some semblance uh but I would like to
put a word of caution because uh we
still have to see a lot more flowing
through. But as things stand in uh first
couple of weeks of April there was
uh definitely much better discipline in
the market.
Yeah sure. Uh secondly can you speak
about IFRS impact on uh our
profitability or ROE any any rough
indication because some of the other
companies are are disclosing their IFRS
number uh which is also quite useful. So
if we can also get some some indication
around that. So so Gopal will give the
indication. My my only point is you know
just to put things in perspective uh
there is an economic value and there is
an accounting value. All these nuance
changes are
eventually on the accounting part of it.
There is obviously an implication in
terms of how positively IRS can help us
but we as an organization would 100%
commit ourselves on the economic value.
Gopal if you can just talk about this I
think spoken we have actually kind of
spoken this even in past calls so
therefore I think our stance would still
be the same as in to say that uh I think
we will continue to evaluate businesses
more on an economic basis because end of
the day that's what will eventually
translate in terms of what is the
outcome that we are writing from a risk
perspective
um transitions to IFRS obviously are
accounting changes which we obviously we
will be uh in that sense well prepared
and at this point of time obviously we
are getting most of our work done
internally whether it is in terms of
understanding the impact of change
getting systems geared up so that as and
when there is a clear regulatory
stipulations as what we have currently
indicated so we will be kind of pretty
much ready with whatever it takes to do
the transition but at the same time I
think what I I think we have been
speaking about also is the fact that as
and when we will eventually transition
to IFRS there will be a lot of in that
sense assumptions uh which will have to
be made by market at large. I think it
is important for again various
stakeholders to ensure consistency in
comparison a need for possibly to see if
we can get a lot more alignment with
some of those assumptions that the
market participants use. So I think our
endeavor is in that direction and which
is what we are working with the council
to see how we can possibly play that
role uh far better at this in the
current times. But obviously internally
we are pretty much well prepared. Uh
major areas of impact I think I already
called out. So in that sense no specific
incremental areas to call out as a part
of the current uh impact assessment uh
that we have done but yes we are we are
ready and we will roll out whenever we
see the uh regulatory timelines coming
into action.
Okay. And then uh when we speak about
economic perspective we are talking more
about ROE and not combined ratio. Right.
This is the operator. Yeah. because end
of the day I think whatever you write
has to kind of translate into a return
to stakeholders through a combination of
what we deliver on underwriting plus
obviously how effectively are we able to
put the cash flows to use so hence to
that extent is what we will kind of be
largely driving as an institution
thank you sir thank you that's it for my
side thanks Nidesh thanks
thank you next question comes from the
line of Singh with MK Global Financial
Services Limit Please go ahead.
Yeah. Hi. Uh good evening. Thank for the
opportunity. Just uh couple of
questions. First one is on uh you know
motor TP. Uh if I see again uh around
915 or close of reserve releases you had
this fiscal. Now of course still you
have not touched your 23 hours if I see
or yeah now uh the backdrop is that the
price hike is not happening. uh do you
see I mean uh the support from reserve
releases to continue to provide you know
the support uh in terms of your motor
TVP claims to to catch up with you know
the uh claims in place and then on that
front also another question related is
that okay industry has seen the kind of
a despite this coming the overall non-cl
expense going up now do you see that
scope next year if the claims were to be
under pressure opex side because now the
March 26 deadline for EOM limits
reaching some kind of a you know uh
sanity prevailing among the some extreme
or aggressive peers would you would that
lead to your opex further improving from
here because at the end of the day
that's a sort of a relative market
related phenomena you cannot outpric
yourself in the market if if the peers
were to improve will that also be kind
of a you know helpful and the second one
on the approve on renewal if I read
correctly India even in Asia resource
capacities uh and pricing both have been
kind of favorable. So in back in that
backdrop does that sort of a help in
terms of your profitability in these
kind of a reinfluence heavy line items
like commercialized. Thanks.
Okay. So maybe I will take the second
part first. I think what you observed is
absolutely right. Uh so so hence
obviously that aids us which is what we
have been kind of talking through. uh I
think the more the market gets sensible
in so far as the need for compliance to
the expense of management guidelines are
concerned that kind of definitely augers
well from an overall market discipline
standpoint. So and therefore and again
as you rightly indicated FI26 is a time
period that the regulator stipulated
within which companies are expected to
tow the line when it comes to meeting
the guidelines on excess of management.
So, so obviously this is something that
uh we would be definitely kind of
closely watching for but at the same
time I'm sure all of you are also kind
of clearly hearing that even the
regulator is wanting to make sure that
as an industry pretty much everyone in
the market kind of follows the
discipline on compliance to expense of
management. So hence uh uh the short
answer is of course it augers well in so
far as uh favorable market development
is concerned and within that uh indeed
obviously that's something that we have
always seen when the market gets far
more sensible on underwriting than
ICumbard by virtue of its uh brand
technology service etc etc is obviously
able to kind of command an incremental
market growth uh without compromising on
underwriting outcomes. So, so that's the
response to the second one. To the
response on the third one, I think with
respect to the reinsurance uh renewal
cycle again, I think you all understand
insurance as much as what we do. Uh so
therefore uh so therefore in that sense
uh uh the the renewals are always
through cycles. You will always see
periods of softness and at some points
of time the market starts to get
hardened. Uh I think the key is end of
the day I think if you look at from our
standpoint what we have again
particularly in the commercial lines
where you relatively see higher
proportion of reinsurance we have
continued to stay disciplined on picking
risks which we think are viable from an
under from a underwriting perspective uh
depend irrespective of which cycle the
market is currently operating at in
terms of uh the reinsurance renewals.
Now that's what is finding favor if you
were to see which is what put out also
on our investor presentation as in to
say that the quality of the partners
with whom we work clearly is kind of
pretty much there. So obviously we don't
in that sense want to take any
unnecessary credit risk. So we are very
very conscious of making sure that we
work with highquality panel of
reinsurers. So that gives us a lot of
comfort when it comes to getting
capacity and also now to your point on
terms obviously it's again we get start
we get terms which are better than the
market. uh so even this year at least
what we understand relative to the
market I think we have been given the
underwriting performance that we have
exhibited to the reinsurers I think we
believe we have been able to get terms
both on commissions and the cost that we
incur for protecting our net uh to be
possibly better than where the market is
placed at and that will again kind of
aid us in our ability to further uh
dwell on incremental market share so
that's in response to the third question
on reinsurance renewal cycle
Your first point on motor third party. I
think again I as I keep saying this u I
think the ranges is what we have spoken
about in terms of the motor loss ratio.
Again I will keep saying we have to look
at motor as in the aggregate and the
range that we have spoken about even in
the earlier earnings call uh for the
segment has been between 65 to 67.
Broadly if you look at the loss ratio
outcome that has played out for even the
current year is pretty much within the
range that we have been kind of talking
about. So hence that's how we look at
now what can happen in case if no third
party price increase sustains for one
more year in FI26 obviously that means
we have to do a lot more work to make
sure that we are able to identify better
risk selection and continue to see how
we can drive profitable go that's what
we will focus on and more importantly
let's say for the market they will have
to work much more harder particularly
for those companies which have combined
with no third party price increase and a
compliance to expense of management
agement yes is something that some of
those market participants will have to
work on. So again we believe we're
getting favorably placed in terms of the
opportunity that one sees on uh motor
third party. And finally on the point on
reserving I think again our approach to
the actial principles pretty much stands
intact. There is absolutely no change in
the way how we have been kind of
reserving for the portfolio in terms of
consistency and that's the reason even
if you would have seen the reserve
redundancy that you would have seen
across key lines we continue to see one
more year of uh reserve redundancy. So
that reflects the quality of reserving
that we have been able to kind of play
up to. So hence no change in the actial
thought process.
Thank you. Very clear. Thanks. Okay.
Thank you. Next question comes from the
line of Shria Shivani with CLSA. Please
go ahead. Hi, thank you for the
opportunity. I have one question that is
on the expense ratio for the quarter. Um
so the way I understood uh the the
impact of the 1 byN accounting last
time. uh the quarters are similar in
terms of what happened in 3Q to 4Q in
terms of the volume growth that you got
or uh how much you have retained then
ideally your expense ratio should have
been similar to what it was in 3Q even
the absolute amount has declined in 4Q
uh if I if I don't talk about the ratio
even the absolute amount has declined so
what has helped us in having much lesser
net commissions at least if if you can
help me understand this is just about
the
quarter Mr. Again it's like it's like
the question that keeps coming to us in
terms of the third party loss experience
on how the loss ratio movement are
happening between quarters. Uh I think
again I will kind of keep reiterating. I
think our our focus is very clearly is
to make sure that expense plus
commissions put together as a company we
are very very conscious of making sure
that we run the overall operations at a
EOM threshold which is less than 30%.
And which is what if you see on a full
year basis I think for us the excess of
management number stands at about
29.5%. Uh so hence I think we're pretty
much committed within a quarter various
factors in terms of business mix in
terms of efficiencies that we always
keep looking for in terms of our own
internal
processes and so there are numerous
factors that go into it. So hence which
is why we keep urging to keep looking at
numbers more on an annual basis rather
than a particular quarter and more so on
an absolute basis I think again there
can be many factors to it. So for
example I mean whenever if there are
periods where I do a lot more of those
investments in that quarter you will see
the cost hitting us uh and and so on. So
a better number to look at will be more
the expense of management number than
anything else. And also share admin
since you're and you're comparing
quarter three and quarter four just to
right it's the configuration of business
that comes in in quarter three we have
far more new book that comes in it's a
season where you know the sale of new
goals our market share motor also grows
in a very very significant way in
January typical Jan also is a reasonably
big line on the commercial side of the
business which can further impact the
expense ratio in a positive manner so
it's more driven by consideration of
what nature of business you write which
creates their
differentiation then that's you know
that when these things happen and you
have a quarter where there's a new
coming in it would impact uh us uh you
know far more uh yeah okay yeah the only
thing I was getting confused that if the
retention ratios are similar between 3Q
and 4Q then your commission rates should
have been similar ideally your net
commission uh ratios but I get the part
that if you've written more commercial
line in 4Q then obviously yeah okay fair
okay thank you thank you
thank you next question comes from the
line of prahar sharma with Jeff please
go ahead
hi good evening uh just wanted to delve
upon comment on you know the uh pricing
stance by some of the PSUs or broader
market in the uh motor vehicle business.
Uh could you just elaborate on this that
uh you know from what segments of uh
general uh GI operators did you see some
bit of an aggressive stance uh and has
there been any change because you know
while we talk about the EOM uh sunset
for FI26
uh are the private ones also genuinely
trying to consolidate on pricing and
second just connected to this is there a
possibility or is there the discussion
around the EOM getting pushed out by a
year or so just so that everybody makes
it without too much exception. Thank
you. Uh so Pakar I think uh on the PSU
aggression uh it's primarily driven very
extensively on the motor side. Uh will
it sustain too early to comment? There
were shades of that visible in quarter
three but quarter four if you see they
have overall buckled the trend and they
have gained significant market share
also in the uh motor segment. Uh it
would be anybody's guess in terms of
what their plan is. Uh we are pretty
ready to face whatever be the you know
trajectory that they have and uh we'll
wait and see how it pans out. uh we
would continue to as I said in my uh you
know in my you know initial remarks that
we would continue to flock woody because
these things can happen at multi
multiple level uh at with multiple
players sometimes it's private sector
sometimes it's public sector but we need
to stick to our trajectory of what we
want to do uh with respect to expense of
management uh deferment uh our
understanding is that uh what has got
called was Poland final. Uh we do
believe it will be it will be good in
long term for the industry if there's a
seminance on that count. Uh we have no
one to comment in terms of whether a
dispensation will be given for another
year. But if you ask a personal belief
another year of dispensation will make
them continue the practice as it exists
and will not change anything because
then they can ask another year of
dispensation. So uh that's where we
would be you know
uh that's where we would leave this part
of the conversation at least.
Perfect. Thank you so much. Yeah thank
you.
Thank you. Next question comes from the
line of Aditi Jooshi with JB Morgan.
Please go ahead.
Uh yeah uh thank you for taking my
question. Uh just a very simple one.
Sorry could not uh go through the
presentation with respect to the
investment income was it uh since the
fourth quarter it was uh lower on an
year basis wanted to understand is it
majorly on account of interest income or
on account of lower uh realized gains
yeah we put that as a part of the
opening script so largely it's because
of uh I mean the nature of how we kind
of real the nature of how we run the
overall investment book the short Answer
is capital gains. Quarter four. Last
year capital gains was roughly about 150
crores plus. This year pretty much our
capital gains is as good as a very very
small number of roughly about 6 crores.
So that's last that's the reason why you
see uh the overall uh investment income
for Q4 of this year to be slightly lower
than the Q4 of last year. But having
said that I think what has worked well
again as I said I think the treasury
team has done a great job in trying to
make sure that the portfolio has got
significantly kind of balanced to make
sure that we go long and hence uh which
is why again time and again we have been
giving the yield to maturity numbers
which used to be less than 7% that
number as we speak currently stands at
about 7.55%. So, so this is for for here
to state and hence uh at least for
quarter four the short answer is capital
gains. Yeah. And also you know something
which I must put across what our
treasury team has done is even over
quarter and quarter we have increased
the yield of the book from 7% to
7.55. So which is a big one with the
tenure also which has gone to 5.34.
uh overall it puts us well in terms of
the current scenario that exists on the
that exists on the you know interest
rate
part and also in quarter three it was
more of a tactical call where our
investment team felt that it was much
better to book capital gains in that
quarter versus what would happen in
quarter four uh in hindsight it did work
out for us
okay that's clear thank Thank you.
Thanks.
Thank you.
Next question comes from the line of NR
to Nal with UPS securities. Please go
ahead. Yeah. Hi. Uh so uh my question is
regarding getting to say how should one
think about the growth given you know
what we have discussed uh there
still as you mentioned and the could be
different than what we try to you know
think about
as sorry to stop you we're not able to
hear you you're not that audible uh is
it better now
yeah if you can just repeat your
question n that will help so so one
question from the on the group side uh
because given this end will kind of
normalize from October.
uh also one thing about overall growth
and the peppered areas will remain
health and obviously motor uh uh there's
been lot of compet density which is you
know increase especially from PSC is
what I understand so any comment on
overall growth we are targeting in FIB6
that is one and second is a booking
question on the other income from the
non-operating reserves which seems to be
very high uh so anything on Right.
So maybe I'll take the first one. Uh I
think on the growth side NRJ uh the good
part is I think if you look at some of
the actions which are being taken both
at both at various governments and even
our own insurance regulator I think the
efforts have been very very positive. I
think for example the recent budget did
see a lot of a lot of uh uh people kind
of getting a higher disposable income
which kind of augers well. Now all of
this will start to kind of play through
maybe over the subsequent uh quarters.
So that's a very very positive action
which comes from the government. Equally
I think regulators are doing their part
in terms of trying to keep relatively
the interest rate of the environment at
far more acceptable levels and the very
recent rate cuts again kind of augers
well in so far as driving uh consumpt
retail consumption and in general
driving consumptions are concerned. So,
so there are clearly lot of positive
factors which should aid when it comes
to let's say growth because ours is a
direct reflection of what happens in so
far as economic activities are concerned
and some of these positive actions by
the government and regulators augers
very very well coupled with this I think
if you look at side for the next two
quarters in general I think we are very
very positively placed in terms of how
we see the opportunity play out and also
what we kind of responded to the earlier
question on how the initial corporate
renewal cycle has been. I think that
looks again very very promising. Now
that's something that has started off on
a positive note right from the beginning
of the year. So hence even for the rest
of the year one should see that cycle
play through. So overall I think we are
kind of positively looking at in terms
of how the market should kind of play
out and within that I think what we have
spoken is to try and see how we can
continue to deliver that outperformance
with the industry growth numbers is what
we will be kind of penciling in first
two quarters you are absolutely right uh
in Nirj in terms of the impact of one by
will obviously kind of play out so maybe
to that extent industry growth could be
a little subdued but on a fullear basis
I think we are very very optimistic
and any uh comment on the combined bas
guidance uh if we are changing or
revising uh giving any new guidance I
think we are see on the guidance part
we've given a complete perspective if
the industry continues to deterate our
own belief would be that uh we are part
of the same pond right so uh you would
see uh overall all challenges but in our
scheme of things if there is improvement
status quo you would see us probably uh
improving more importantly it's the ROE
part of it which we would focus on and
see what kind of returns we are able to
generate and in that we've always m
maintained that we want to see at least
16 to you know 20% kind of range for us
as a company being given to stakeholders
uh so now the bookkeeping of the other
income uh the nonoperating results you
very high. Is it something regrouping or
if you can show?
Yeah, nothing specific but it is it is
business as usual for us. They will all
be driven by whatever the regulatory
stipulations are. Uh and uh no no
specific changes per se. Oh thank you.
Thank you ladies and gentlemen. Due to
time constraints we have reached the end
of question and answer session. I would
now like to hand the conference over to
Mr. Sanjiv Mantri for closing comments.
Hi, I think uh great to connect with all
of you. Uh closure of uh another
financial year and uh some exciting
times awaits. Look forward to
interacting with each one of you uh as
and when your time permits. uh we do
believe that general insurance industry
is poised for a decent year uh going
forward and we would keep in touch and
keep you updated. Thank you so much for
joining in and all the best to each one
of you. Thank you so much.
Thank you on behalf of ICIC Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited. That
concludes this conference. Thank you for
joining us. You may now disconnect your
lines.